Inventory of the Lina Nancy Potter Papers 1942-1945
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Lina Nancy Potter Papers 1942-1945
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2007.55
0.20
28 items
Correspondence, photographs, and military papers concerning the World War II service of 2nd Lt. A.N.C. Lina Nancy Potter (1901-1975) of Narragansett, Rhode Island. Potter enlisted in the United States Armed Forces in 1942 and served as a nurse in a military hospital in India from 1943-1945. This collection consists of 23 letters of her outgoing wartime correspondence to family (her Aunt Harriet E. Weaver and Uncle Charles Weaver of Rhode Island) in the United States, her military papers, and three wartime photographs of Potter and her fellow nurses. Potter's correspondence is of special interest because Potter was allowed to censor her own letters (perhaps because she was an officer) before they were sent to the United States. Thus, Potter's correspondence contains a log of wartime conditions at a hospital near Burma, India. Her letters discuss poor food and housing conditions, status of her work in India, the war in India and China, and aspects relative to women's history during the Second World War.
Potter, Lina Nancy, 1907-1975 arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center from ebay.com on 04/22/2007.
Biographical Note
Lina Nancy Potter (1901-1975) of Narragansett, Rhode Island, enlisted in the United States Armed Forces in 1942 and served as a 2nd Lt. A.N.C. nurse in a military hospital in India from 1943-1945. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Lina Nancy Potter.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, photographs, and military papers concerning the World War II service of 2nd Lt. A.N.C. Lina Nancy Potter (1901-1975) of Narragansett, Rhode Island. Potter enlisted in the United States Armed Forces in 1942 and served as a nurse in a military hospital in India from 1943-1945. This collection consists of 23 letters of her outgoing wartime correspondence to family (her Aunt Harriet E. Weaver and Uncle Charles Weaver of Rhode Island) in the United States, her military papers, and three wartime photographs of Potter and her fellow nurses. Potter's correspondence is of special interest because Potter was allowed to censor her own letters (perhaps because she was an officer) before they were sent to the United States. Thus, Potter's correspondence contains a log of wartime conditions at a hospital near Burma, India. Her letters discuss poor food and housing conditions, status of her work in India, the war in India and China, and aspects relative to women's history during the Second World War.
Arrangement of Materials
Collection has been arranged into three series: Series I: Correspondence, Series II: Military Papers, and Series III: Photographs. Correspondence has been arranged chronologically.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Certificates; Correspondence; Photographs
Topical Term:
India--History--20th century.; Medicine, Military--India.; United States--Women--History; World War, 1939-1945--Medical and sanitary affairs.; World War, 1939-1945--Pacific Area; World War, 1939-1945.
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Lina N. Potter WWII Papers, id2125 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1945; id2103 (Box 1)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1 item, 1942; id2126 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 10 items, 1943; id2097 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 6 items, 1944; id2098 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 5 items., 1945; id2099 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1 item., id2100 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Military Papers, 1942-1945; id2104 (Box 1)
    - Military papers, vaccination record and nursing certificate, 2 items, 1942-1946; id2101 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, circa 1942-1945; id2105 (Box 1)
    - Photographs, two of Potter and one of her fellow nurses in India, circa 1942-1945; id2102 (Box 1, Folder 7)